{
    "id": "f81d54ba4fd046bc961c00a8aad42076",
    "title": "Articles with countable and uncountable nouns",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "d7354de4493848e5b13b3f2c53757fd4",
            "title": "Articles With Uncountable And Countable Nouns",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We are having .......................... weather.",
                    "description": "Weather is an uncountable noun. We cannot use the articles a/an with it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "awful",
                        "an awful",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Have you got ............................ for dry skin?",
                    "description": "Sometimes uncountable nouns are treated as countable to express the meaning 'a type of'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "cold cream",
                        "a cold cream",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We have made ............................. progress.",
                    "description": "Progress is an uncountable noun and it cannot be used with the article a.",
                    "answers": [
                        "good",
                        "a good",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The applicant should be able to speak ..................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "a good English",
                        "good English",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We haven't seen ......................... in days.",
                    "description": "We use the article 'the' to talk about something unique. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "sun",
                        "the sun",
                        "a sun"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "How did ....................... first discover fire?",
                    "description": "The noun 'man' is commonly used to mean 'the human race'. No articles are used in this case. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "man",
                        "the man",
                        "a man"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "...................... have their own language and culture.",
                    "description": "The Irish means all people belonging to Ireland. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Irish",
                        "The Irish",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "My children like ............................. but I prefer ...........................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "the sea, mountains",
                        "sea, mountains",
                        "the sea, the mountains"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................ are losing hope.",
                    "description": "The unemployed means all unemployed people. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Unemployed",
                        "The unemployed",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This engine does not use ......................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "petrol",
                        "the petrol",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................... is quite complicated.",
                    "description": "No article is used when we talk about the whole of life. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Life",
                        "The life",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am studying ........................ of Lincoln.",
                    "description": "We use the article 'the' here because we are talking about one particular life. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "life",
                        "the life",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}